《猛鬼街》
蒂娜
Tina...
Tina!
你没事吧  蒂娜
You OK, Tina?
只是做了一个恶梦  妈
Just a dream, Ma.
做了一个疯狂的恶梦
Some dream, judging from that.
回到床上来  老婆
You coming back to the sack or what?
你先回去
Hold your horses.
蒂娜  你必须修剪指甲
Tina, honey, you got to cut your fingernails...
就可以不做恶梦
or you got to stop that kind of dreaming.
其中一个必须做到
One or the other.
一  二  佛莱迪要来抓你了
One... two... Freddy's coming for you.
三  四  锁好你的门
Three... four... Better lock your door.
五  六  快去拿十字架
Five... six... Grab your crucifix.
七  八  彻夜不眠
Seven... eight... Gonna stay up late.
九  十  永远不要睡
Nine... ten... Never sleep again...
真可怕
It was so scary.
我醒来后他好像还在房间内
When I woke up...
就像传说中的妖怪
It seemed like he was still in the room with me.
好像是一个鬼怪专程来找你
Sounds like a real bogeyman.
一  二  佛莱迪要来抓你了
"One... two... Freddy's coming for you."
那使我想起那一首跳绳童谣
That's what it reminded me of... that old jump rope song.
那是我所做过最可怕的恶梦
It was the worst nightmare I ever had.
你一定不会相信的
You wouldn't believe it.
事实上我自己也做了一个恶梦
As a matter of fact, I had a bad dream last night myself.
我今天早上起床时勃起  蒂娜
I had a hard-on this morning when I woke up, Tina.
而你的名字一直在我脑中盘旋
Had your name written all over it.
我的名字有4个字母  罗德
There's four letters in my name, Rod.
你为什么想的都是4个字母的人
How could there be room on your joint for four letters?
祝你有个美梦  罗德真会卖乖
Hey! Up yours with a twirling lawnmower. Rod says the sweetest things.
他很可爱
He's nuts about you.
对  是讨人厌
Yeah, nuts. Anyway...
说真的  我昨晚无法入眠
I couldn't go back to sleep last night.
你做了什么梦
So, what did you dream?
忘了它吧  蒂娜
Forget it, Tina.
每个人偶尔都会做梦的
The point is that everyone has a bad dream once in a while.
这不是什么严重的事
It's no biggie.
下次你再做恶梦时  就跟自己说
Next time you're having one, just tell yourself...
当你遇到时才是真的
that's all it is right while you're having it.
过了之后就没事了
Once you do that, you wake right up.
至少我是如此
At least, it works for me.
你也做了恶梦
Did you have a nightmare, too?
也许快要有大地震了
Maybe we're going to have a big earthquake.
传说在地震前都会变的怪怪的
They say things get really weird just before.
真高兴你们今天晚上到我家来
I'm so glad you guys could come over tonight.
我听我妈说她要离开几天时  我担心死了
When my mom said she was taking off for two days, I almost died.
不必怕  蒂娜  南希和格伦来搭救你
No problem, Tina. Nancy and Glen to the rescue.
我不敢相信他妈说他也做恶梦
I can't believe his mother's letting him spend the night.
是  事实上她不是这意思
Right, well... she's not exactly.
上次我到机场接我表弟
See, I got this cousin who lives near the airport.
他想暂时住在我家
It's OK for me to stay with him.
罗德给我这一盒录音带
And I got this sound effects tape from Rod...
哈罗  妈
Hello, Mom?
对  贝利如何了
Yeah. Out here at Barry's.
对  和以前一样吵
Yeah, noisy as usual.
还好你没住在这里
Glad we don't live here, huh?
对  享利在向你打招呼
Aunt Eunice says hello.
好  我明早打电话给你
I'll call you in the morning.
对  对  好
Yeah, sure...
外面有一些小鬼在开快车
Just some kids drag racing outside, I think, Mom.
妈  我要走了
Listen, Mom. I gotta go.
外面好像有车祸
I think there's been an accident out front.
对  我去叫警察
All right, I'll call the police.
好  我去叫警察
I'll call the police!
不  只是邻居们在吵架
Just some neighbors having a fight, I guess.
没事
I'm fine.
我明早打电话给你
I'll call you in the morning.
你真像巫师
It worked like a charm.
没错
Smooth.
老天爷
Jesus.
你看  我说过你会好一点的
See? I told you you'd be feeling better.
我一直看到那家伙的怪异脸孔
All day long I've been seeing that guy's weird face...
常出现在他的指甲旁
and hearing those fingernails.
指甲
Fingernails?
真令我感到意外
That's amazing you saying that.
我昨晚也做了一个同样的梦
That made me remember the dream I had last night.
你做了什么梦
What did you dream?
我梦到一个穿着红绿相间毛衣的男人
I dreamed about a guy in a dirty red and green sweater.
指甲呢
What about the fingernails?
除了指甲还有其他的
He scraped his fingernails along things.
其实  那些指甲更像是刀片
Actually, they were more like finger-knives...
看来是自制的
something he made himself.
还发出怪声音
But they made a horrible sound.
听起来就像
It was like...
南希  你和我梦到的怪胎
You dreamed about the same creep I did.
不可能的
That's impossible.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
外面有东西是吗
There's something out there, isn't there?
我没听到
I didn't hear anything.
我听到了
I heard something.
不管你是谁  我要你见光死
I'm going to punch out your lights, whoever you are.
喵喵
Kitty, kitty.
汪汪
Chow, chow, chow?
罗德在三尺之外
It's Rod Lane bringing Lantz down...
终于把格伦推到在地
just three yards from the goal line!
真是一次漂亮的转倒
What a brilliant tackle, and the fans go wild!
你在这里做什么
What the hell are you doing here?
只是个恶作剧  不必在意
Came to make up. No big deal.
你妈在吗
Your mom home?
当然在  那是什么
Of course. What's that?
很可怕是不是
Intense, huh?
这里怎么回事  不狂欢了吗
What's going on here, an orgy or something?
也许有葬礼  呆子
Maybe a funeral, dickhead.
只是来陪蒂娜  罗德
It's just a sleep-over date, Rod.
我是来陪蒂娜  格伦刚要离开
Tina and me. Glen was just leaving.
你看到他那样子没
Did you see his face?
你妈不在家  对吧
Your mom ain't home, is she?
我和蒂娜有事要谈
Me and Tina got stuff to discuss.
你们可以到她房间的床休息
We got her mother's bed.
你们自便
You guys got the rest.
我想我们应该离开
I think we should get out of here.
你们不是要留下吗
You guys are going to hang around, right?
不要把我和这疯子留下
Don't leave me alone with this lunatic.
求求你  南希
Please, Nancy?
格伦  现在不要
Glen, not now.
我们要陪着蒂娜  不要太自私
We're here for Tina now, not ourselves.
她为什么老是被可笑的恶梦困扰
Why is she so bothered by a stupid nightmare anyway?
因为她很怕
Because he was scary, that's why!
道德沦亡
Morality sucks.
我知道我喜欢你某一些优点
I knew there was something about you I liked.
你觉得好一点了吗
You feel better now?
我们是天作之合
Jungle man fix Jane.
不再吵架了
No more fights?
不再吵架
No more fights.
晚上睡觉不再做恶梦
No more nightmares for either one of us, then.
你什么时候做过恶梦
When did you have a nightmare?
男人也会做恶梦  你知道吗
Guys can have nightmares, too, you know.
我们不能靠购物来减压
You ain't got a corner on the market.
你以为你是谁
Who do you think you are?
不管你是谁
Whoever you are.
有人吗
Somebody there?
到底是谁
Who the hell is that?
可恶
Shit.
上帝
Please, God...
看这个
This...
就是上帝
is God.
看这个
Watch this.
南希  快开门
Nancy! Open the door!
罗德  救命
Rod, help me!
救我  罗德  救我  罗德
Help me, Rod!
我要杀了你  是谁干的
Who did this? I'll kill you!
到底谁干的
Who did this?
天哪  你吓死我了
You scared me!
有什么资料  她叫蒂娜  格雷  那是她家
What have you got? Her name was Tina Gray. It was her home.
她父亲十年前离家出走
Father abandoned, 10 years ago.
母亲和男友在拉斯维加斯
Mother's in Vegas with a boyfriend.
我们正在想办法联络他
We're trying to reach her now.
验尸官怎么说
What's the coroner got?
应该是被利器所杀
Something like a razor was the weapon...
但现场没发现任何凶器
but nothing was found at the scene.
一看之下好像是被男友害的
It looks like the victim's boyfriend.
她在哪里
Lieutenant, where is she?
带她到你的办公室
I put her in your office.
他叫罗德蓝尔
His name's Rod Lane.
热爱音乐
He's a musician type.
曾因吸毒和打架被捕
He's been arrested for drugs, brawling.
太棒了  他在那里做什么
Terrific. What the hell was she doing there?
他住哪里
She lived there.
我不是说他
I don't mean her.
我是说你
I mean you.
她在那里做什么
What was she doing there?
你好  唐诺
Hello to you, too, Donald.
马奇  没事了
Marge. OK.
感觉如何  宝贝
How you doing, baby?
我没事  爸
I'm OK, Dad.
好  我要了解情况
Look, I don't want to get into this now.
要一点时间
God knows you need time.
但我最想知道的是
But I sure would like to know what the hell you were doing...
你为什么在三更半夜和三个小孩子鬼混
shacking up with three kids in the middle of the night...
特别是和那个丧心病狂的蓝尔一起
especially a lunatic delinquent like Lane.
罗德不是丧心病狂  爸
Rod is not a lunatic, Dad.
你对他所做的有何解释
You have a sane explanation for what he did?
显然他是妒而发狂
Apparently, he was crazy jealous.
南希说他们在吵架
Nancy said they'd had a fight.
并没那么严重
It wasn't that serious.
也许你不认为谋杀是严重的事
Maybe you don't think murder is serious.
你怎么知道那会变成严重的事
How can you say I don't take her death seriously?
我是说
Look, all I meant...
他们并不是吵得那么严重
was that their fights weren't that serious.
你知道吗  蒂娜她  她梦到这可能会发生
You know Tina dreamed this was going to happen.
什么事
What?
她有一个恶梦  有人想杀她
She'd had a nightmare that someone was trying to kill her.
所以我们才到她家  妈
That's why we were there, Mom.
她不敢一个  人睡
She just didn't want to sleep alone.
警方说15岁的蒂娜·格雷
Police say the victim, 15-year-old Christina Gray...
曾和男友罗德蓝尔争吵过
had quarreled earlier with her boyfriend Rod Lane.
蓝尔现在被囚禁于市立看守所
Lane is now the subject of a citywide manhunt.
至于杀人凶器
The murder weapon...
估计是某种利刃  但至今仍未找到
a straight razor or similar sharp object, has not yet...
你要去哪里
Where do you think you're going?
上学
To school.
亲爱的  我们昨晚谈了一夜
Honey, you were tossing and turning all night last night.
你知道今天最好不要上学
You have no business going to school today.
我必须要去学校  妈
I've got to go to school, Mother.
否则我坐在那里会发疯
Otherwise, I'll sit up there and go crazy.
你有没有睡觉
Did you sleep?
我到图书室去睡
I'll sleep in study hall.
我宁愿自己忙一点
I'd rather keep busy.
放学就马上回来
Right home after?
我知道了
Right home after.
再见
See you.
我不会伤害你  不会伤害你的
I'm not going to hurt you!
他们会杀死我的
They're going to kill me for sure.
没人会杀你
Nobody's going to kill you.
是你做的吗
Did you do it?
我根本没碰到她
I never touched her.
你像疯子似地尖叫
You were screaming like crazy.
那房间里有个  人在
There was somebody else there.
房门是从里面锁着的
The door was locked from your side!
不要用那种好像我是杀人狂的眼神看我
Don't look at me like I'm some fucking fruitcake!
我信任你
I'm warning you!
不要碰她  小鬼
Just move away from her, son.
只要你不要乱动就没事
Real easy, like your ass depended on it.
站住
Hold it!
老天爷
Jesus Christ!
站住不要动
Hold it right there!
我不动
Watch it!
好  我逮到他了
I'm cool!
趴在地上  快
I got him. On the ground! Now!
过来  趴下
Come on! Get down!
队长  看这个  是弹簧刀
Lieutenant, look at this! A switchblade!
不是我干的  我没杀她  南希
I didn't do it! I didn't kill her, Nancy!
爸  你竟然利用我
Daddy? You used me.
你这是要干嘛
What the hell were you doing...
今天还要回学校吗
going to school today for anyway?
放手
Let go of my arm!
你所看到的  有时不是真的
What is seen is not always what is real.
根据莎士比亚的说法  大自然之中
According to Shakespeare, there was something operating...
甚至是人的本性中  都有腐败的部分
in nature, perhaps inside human nature itself, that was rotten.
他称之为"腐败源头"
"A canker," as he put it.
哈姆雷特因此而走入魔道
Of course, Hamlet's response to this...
对于母亲撒的谎  他不断去查探
and to his mother's lies was to continually probe and dig.
就像挖墓一样
Just like the gravediggers...
不断往下挖
always trying to get beneath the surface.
却有点不同
The same is true in a different way...
在凯撒
in Julius Caesar.
约翰  请念下一段
John, will you go ahead, please?
在罗马最鼎盛之时
"In the most high and palmy state of Rome...
凯撒大帝却突然驾崩
A little ere the mightiest Julius fell.
他未能安然入土
The grave stood tenantless...
遗体在罗马的大街小巷中
and the sheeted dead did squeak and gibber...
默默诉怨
in the Roman streets."
星宿带着烈焰  充斥着血腥味
"As stars with trains of fire and dues of blood...
太阳使得空气无比闷热
"disaster's in the sun and the moist air...
受海王星支配的帝国
"upon whose influence Neptune's empire stands..."
老天
"Oh, God, I could be bounded in a nutshell...
我愿困在坚壳中
"and count myself a king of infinite space...
自诩为无尽宇宙的君王  在那里  不会再有恶梦
"were it not that I have bad dreams."
你的早退条呢
Where's your pass?
别烦我
Screw your pass.
南希  不准在走廊奔跑
Hey, Nancy! No running in the hallway.
你是谁
Who are you?
抓到你了
Gonna get you.
这只是一场恶梦
It's only a dream!
来佛莱迪这儿吧
Come to Freddy.
你去死
God damn you!
没事了  南希
OK! OK! Thompson!
我叫你妈来
I'll call your mother.
现在没事了
Everything is all right now.
坐下  不
Come on. Sit down.
我没事
I'm OK.
我很好
I'm fine.
你确定吗
You sure?
我要回来
I'll go straight home.
你需要早退条
You'll need a hall pass.
继续上课
Back to work.
后来呢
And then what happened?
我告诉过你
I told you.
当时很暗  但我确定有个人在
It was dark, but I'm sure there was somebody in there...
在床单下面和她在一起
under the covers with her.
怎么会有个人在床单下
How could somebody be under the covers with you guys...
你怎么会不知道
without you knowing about it?
我怎么会知道
How the fuck do I know?
反正我不期望你相信我
I don't expect you to believe me anyway.
那人长什么样
What did he look like?
你没看到他吗
Did you get a look at him?
那你怎么知道被子下面有个人在
Then how do you know that somebody else was there?
因为我看到有人在用东西割她
Because somebody cut her while I watched.
但你却没看到凶手
And you didn't get a look at him?
我看不到那混蛋
I couldn't even see the fucker.
只看得到
You could just see...
割的情形
cuts happening...
突然出现
all at once.
"突然出现"是什么意思
What do you mean all at once?
就像是有四把利刃
It was as if there were four razors...
同时在割她
cutting her at the same time...
但看不到
but invisible ones.
我想我可以救她
You know, I probably could have saved her...
但己来不及了
if I'd have moved sooner.
我后来想这可能是恶梦
But I thought it was just another nightmare...
和我前几天做的恶梦一样
like the one I had the night before.
是那个  人
There was this guy.
他有像刀子的指甲
He had knives for fingers.
你还认为是我干的吗
You think I did it?
一  二
One... two...
佛莱迪要来抓你了
Freddy's coming for you.
三  四  锁好你的门
Three... four...
最好把门锁紧
Better lock your door.
五  六
Five... six...
快去拿十字架
Grab your crucifix.
七  八
Seven... eight...
彻夜不眠
Gonna stay up late.
九  十  你会睡不着
Nine... ten...
永远不要睡
Never sleep... again.
什么事  妈妈
What, Mother?
洗澡时别睡觉
Don't fall asleep in there.
会被溺死的
You could drown, you know.
拜托
Oh, for Pete's sakes.
这种事常有发生的
It happens all the time.
我为你泡了热牛奶  亲爱的
I've heated up some warm milk for you, honey.
热牛奶
Warm milk?
没兴趣
Gross.
救命
Help!
坚持住  宝贝
Hold on, baby!
妈
Mom!
我没事
I'm OK.
- 还好吗  - 我没事
- You're OK? - I'm OK.
我听到你在叫救命
But I heard you screaming. You were calling me.
我只是滑到浴池底下了  妈
I just slipped getting out of the tub, Mom.
我告诉过你
But I told you...
很多人这样而溺死
hundreds of people a year get killed like that, honey.
我知道  我没事  妈
I know, but I'm OK, Mother.
对不起  吓着了你
I'm sorry for scaring you.
不要紧  我帮你铺床好吗
I'll turn down your bed.
好的  我先去换睡衣
I'll get my pajamas on.
把躯体一块块进行肢解
...the act of bodily dismemberment.
对不起  我看到你的灯还亮着
I'm sorry. I saw your light was on.
所以来看看你情况如何
I thought I'd see how you were.
有时我希望你不是住在对街
Sometimes I wish you didn't live right across the street.
不要说了  让我进去
Will you shut up and let me in?
赤脚站在花棚上可不舒服
Did you ever stand on a trellis in your bare feet?
趁没人发现快点进来
Get inside before somebody sees you.
我撞到头了
I hit my head.
小声一点  我妈还没睡
Gotta be quiet. Mom's not even asleep yet.
如果您不介意
If you don't mind.
听说昨天上英文课时你突然尖叫
So, I heard you freaked out in English class today.
没错
Yeah, I guess I did.
你还没睡吗
You haven't slept yet, have you?
还没
Not really.
你的手怎么了
What did you do to your arm?
上英文课时烫伤的
I burned it in English class.
老天  我已经二十岁  了
Oh, God. I look 20 years old.
你昨晚是否有做奇怪的梦
Did you have any weird dreams last night?
我睡得跟死猪一样
Slept like a rock.
你相信人可以
Do you believe that people...
梦到将发生的事吗
can dream about what's going to happen?
不相信
No.
你相信有鬼怪存在吗
Do you believe in the bogeyman?
不相信
No.
罗德杀了蒂娜  你知道的
Rod killed Tina, and you know that.
我想你帮我个大忙
I've got a crazy favor to ask you.
很容易的
It's nothing hard or anything.
我要去找一个人
I'm gonna go and look for somebody...
我希望你当我的警卫  好吗
and I want you to stand... like a sort of a guard, OK?
千万别搞砸了
Now, you can't mess up.
这件事很重要
A lot might depend on this.
我不会搞砸的
I won't screw up.
把灯关掉
Turn off the light.
好  我们的计划是这样
Here's what we're going to do.
这里好黑
It's dark in here.
你不要想歪了
And it's not what you're thinking.
你还在看吗
Are you still watching?
对  怎么了
Yeah. So?
我只是想确定一下
I'm just checking.
南希
Watch out!
格伦
醒醒
Wake up!
你还在吗
Are you there?
我在这里
I'm here.
南希  救命
Nancy, help me, please.
快救我
Save me from...
佛莱迪来了
Freddy!
这是梦
This is just a dream.
只是个梦  不是真的
This isn't real.
不是真的
This is just a dream.
他不是真的
He isn't real.
格伦  你这混蛋
Glen, you bastard.
我做了什么
What did I do?
我只要你帮我做一件事
I just asked you to do one thing...
就是叫你看着我
just stay awake and watch me...
我一做恶梦时你就把我叫醒
just wake me up if it looked like I was having a bad dream...
结果呢
and what did you do?
你这混球
You shit.
你竟然睡着了
You fell asleep.
糟了
Oh, shit.
快点
Hurry.
留在这里  不要离开
Shut up and stay there. Don't go away.
你还好吧
Are you OK?
没事  我只是做梦而己
Yeah. It was just a little dream, that's all.
我要继续睡了
I'm going right back to sleep.
好吧  有需要随时叫我好吗
Call me if you need anything.
告诉我发生什么事好吗
You mind telling me what's going on?
跟我来
Just come on.
加西亚  我必须再看罗德一次
Garcia, I've got to see Rod Lane again.
听我说  我值夜班
You know, I took the night shift...
我希望能得到一点宁静
so I could get some peace and quiet.
这件事很紧急
It's urgent!
我们有理由相信
We have reason to believe that there might be...
这里将会发生非常奇怪的事
something very strange going on here.
不用再说了
Got no argument with that.
你在这做什么
What are you doing here?
他是杀人嫌疑犯
There's an unsolved murder...
我最讨厌那种人
and I don't like unsolved murders...
他会把我的女儿给带坏
especially ones that my daughter's mixed up in.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
这时候你应该在家里睡觉
At this hour, you should be home in bed.
你只是来看他是否安好
I just want to see if he's OK.
南希  相信我
Nancy, take my word for it.
这家伙像个婴儿熟睡着
The guy's sleeping like a baby.
他不会乱跑的
He's not going anywhere.
下去看一下好吗
Just go down and look at him.
求求你  爸
Please, Daddy.
好吧
All right.
加西亚  钥匙给我
Garcia, give me the keys.
好吧
Right.
钥匙在哪里
Where the hell did I put the keys?
救命
Help! Help!
爸  老天
Jesus!
快把他放下来
Cut him down.
抓住他的腿
Grab his legs.
我抓住了
I got him.
抓他的背部  你会吗
Grab his back, would you?
放下来
Lower him.
尘归尘
Ashes to ashes...
土归土
Dust to dust.
愿上帝保佑这个年轻的灵魂
May God be with this young man's soul.
他的生与死
His life and his death...
是为圣经作证言
attest to the scriptures' warning...
生死之瞬间
that he who lives by the sword shall die by the sword.
但是  我们要记住它的警告
But let us recall also our Lord's admonition...
我们不审判人  就不会被审判
that we judge not, lest we be judged.
愿罗德蓝尔安息
And may Rod Lane rest in peace.
该走了  亲爱的
Time to go, honey.
上车
Hop in.
杀人者还逍遥法外
The killer's still loose, you know?
你是说杀蒂娜的另有他人
You're saying somebody else killed Tina?
是谁
Who?
我不知道他是谁
I don't know who he is...
但他被烧焦  他头上戴顶奇怪的帽子
but he's burned, and he wears a weird hat...
穿着件肮脏的红绿毛衣
and a red and green sweater, really dirty...
他的巨大手指像刀子一样
and he uses these knives, like giant fingernails.
你最好让她待在家里
You better keep her home for a few days...
等几天之后她恢复神智
until she really gets over the shock of this.
我有个更好的办法
I've got something better.
我要求找人帮我
I'm going to get her some help.
你们可不可以给我一些
I don't see why you couldn't just give me a pill...
不会做梦的药丸
to keep me from dreaming.
每个人都会做梦  小姐
Everyone's got to dream, young lady.
如果你不做梦  那表示没救了
If you don't dream, you go.
好了
All set.
别担心  南希  信任我们
Please, Nancy, trust us.
不是不信任  只是
It's not you I don't trust. It's just...
试就试吧
Let's do it.
谢谢你  护士
Thank you, nurse.
她何时开始这样的
How long has this been going on?
自从凶案发生后
Since the murders.
之前她都没事的
She was fine before that.
现在她以为她的梦是真实的
Now she thinks her dreams are real.
她的脑电图没有问题
There's no sign of pathology in her EEG.
看来只是因为出事后
I'd guess that what we have is just a normal girl...
她吓坏了才会这样
who happens to have gone through two days of hell.
她睡了
She's asleep now.
太好了
Thank God.
到底是什么梦
What the hell are dreams anyway?
没人知道
Mysteries.
那是人体的奥秘
Incredible body hocus-pocus.
事实上我们不知道梦是什么
The truth is we still don't know what they are...
也不知道梦从何而来
or where they come from.
她进入深睡状态了
She's going into deep sleep now.
心跳速度快了一点
Heart rate is a little high.
只是因为紧张而已
It's just due to anxiety.
大致上还是很放松的
Otherwise, she's nicely relaxed.
其他一切正常
All signs are normal.
她现在会随时做梦
She could dream at any time now.
脑波缓慢
Beta waves are slowing.
眼球正快速转动
She's into REMs now.
现在正在做梦
She's definitely dreaming now.
正常
It's a good one, too.
典型的梦形态
Typical dream parameter.
恶梦通常会跳至正负五至六
A nightmare now would be plus or minus five or six.
她只到三
She's about three.
医生  她现在怎么了
Doctor, what's she doing now?
她是睡着还是醒着
Is she asleep or awake?
有点不对劲  指数从没跳到那么高
Something's wrong. It never gets this high.
她怎么了
What's she doing?
我不知道
I don't know.
她在做梦吗
Is she dreaming?
南希  我是妈妈
Nancy, it's Mom!
天哪
What?
她的头发
Her hair.
请让一下
Excuse me.
这个会有助于她睡眠
This'll help you sleep.
天哪  她的手
Oh, my God, her arm!
快止血
Get something.
怎么了  宝贝
What happened, baby?
怎么了
What happened?
不要紧
It's OK.
我在梦里带了东西出来
I brought something out from my dream.
这是哪里来的
Where did you get that?
从他头上扯下来的
I grabbed it off his head.
她说是在梦里从他头上扯下来的
She said she grabbed it off his head in her dream.
不  我没有疯
No, I'm not crazy.
我现在就拿着那顶帽子
I'm holding the damn thing right here in my hand.
我不知道她在那里弄来的
I don't know where she really found it.
我先挂了
I gotta go.
你昨天都没睡吗
You didn't sleep at all last night, did you?
大夫说一定要睡
You know the doctor says you have to sleep, or...
这样我会更疯狂的
I'll go even crazier?
我想你不会疯狂的
I don't think you're crazy.
不要再喝咖啡
And stop drinking that damn coffee.
你有没有叫爸去查那顶帽子
So, did you ask Daddy to have the hat examined?
我把那脏东西丢掉了
I threw that filthy thing away.
我不知道你在哪里找来的
I don't know where you really found it...
也不知道你要证明什么
or what you're trying to prove.
我在睡眠中心学到的
What I learned in the dream clinic...
就是要寻找证据来证明  妈
that's what I'm trying to prove, Mother.
罗德没杀死蒂娜  他也没上吊自杀
Rod didn't kill Tina, and he didn't hang himself.
是那个人
It's this guy.
他在梦里追杀我们
He's after us in our dreams.
这不是真实的  南希
That's just not reality, Nancy.
这是真的  妈
It's real, Mama.
你摸摸看
Feel it.
给我那鬼东西
Give me that damn thing.
帽子里还写有他的名字
It even has his name written in it.
佛莱迪  克鲁格  妈
Fred Krueger, Mom.
你知道那是谁吗  妈
Do you know who that is, Mother?
如果你知道你最好告诉我
Because if you do, you better tell me...
因为他现在正在追杀我
because he's after me now.
南希  你就相信妈妈一次吧
Nancy, trust your mother for once, please.
你睡觉以后会觉得好一点的
You'll feel better when you get some sleep.
好点
Feel better?
这也叫好点吗
You call this feeling better?
也许我真该和你一样
Or maybe I should grab that bottle and veg out with you.
整天一醉方休  我好好做个乖乖女  你就万事无忧了
Avoid everything happening to me by just getting good and loaded.
佛莱迪不可能追杀你  南希
Fred Krueger can't come after you, Nancy.
他死了  相信我
He's dead. Believe me.
是真的
I know.
原来你早就知道这个人
You knew about him all this time...
但你却只当我一直在胡说八道
and you've been acting like it was something I made up?
南希  你病了
Nancy, you're sick.
你出了点小毛病
There's something wrong with you.
你在胡思乱想
You're imagining things.
你睡觉后应该会觉得很好
You'll feel better when you sleep.
非常简单
It's just as simple as that.
我不睡觉
Screw sleep!
那只是个恶梦
It's just a nightmare.
我听够了
That's enough.
我一紧张便狂吃东西
Whenever I get nervous, I eat.
没东西吃时便睡觉
And if you can't do that, you sleep.
我以前也是
I used to.
现在不会了
Not anymore.
你听过巴厘岛土著的做梦方式吗
Did you ever read about the Balinese way of dreaming?
他们有一套做梦技巧
They got this whole system they call dream skills.
假如我做梦时  例如梦到我往下坠落
So if you have a nightmare, for instance, like falling.
怎样
Right.
他们说除了吓得大叫外
Well, instead of screaming and getting all nuts...
还可以说  我要改变想法
you say, "I'm going to make up my mind...
我正跌入魔法世界
"that I fall into a magic world."
他们把恶梦变成美梦
Make it something special like a poem or a song.
他们的文学  艺术都由梦境而来
They get all their art and literature from dreams.
一睡醒便立刻将所梦到的记下来
Just wake up and write it down.
那就是做梦技巧
Dream skills.
如果在梦中遇到怪物怎么办
What if they meet a monster in their dreams?
他们会远离怪物
They turn their back on it.
夺走怪物的力量  令它消失
Take away its energy, and it disappears.
如果不这样做会如何
But what happens if they don't do that?
那些人可能就无法醒来跟你现身说法了
Then I guess those people don't wake up to tell what happens.
太棒了
Great.
害人陷阱及伤人装置
"Booby Traps & lmprovised Anti-Personnel Devices"?
你怎么看这种书
What are you reading that for?
我想存活
I'm into survival.
再见
See ya.
我越来越担心你了
You're starting to scare me.
见鬼
Oh, gross.
妈
Mother!
那些铁栏是怎么回事
What's with the bars?
以防安全
Security.
以防什么安全
Security from what?
不防什么  是防人
Not from what, from whom.
跟我来地窖  我们慢慢谈
Come down to the cellar with me, and I'll tell you.
你想知道谁是佛莱迪  克鲁格
You want to know who Fred Krueger was?
他是个专杀小孩的变态杀手
He was a filthy child murderer...
至少在这附近杀了二十个小孩
who killed at least 20 kids in the neighborhood.
全都是街坊
Kids we all knew.
妈
Oh, Mom.
我们不知道凶手是他时  都很害怕
It drove us crazy when we didn't know who it was...
但他被捕后  情况更糟
but it was even worse after they caught him.
他们放了他吗
Did they put him away?
律师赚了大钱  法官也出了名
The lawyers got fat and the judge got famous...
但是有人忘了在逮捕令的
but somebody forgot to sign the search warrant...
适当地方上签名
in the right place...
于是克鲁格就这样逍遥法外
and Krueger was free just like that.
你们后来怎么做了  妈
What did you do, Mother?
我们好些家长四处去寻找他
A bunch of us parents tracked him down...
想把他逮回来
after they let him out.
最后在废弃的锅炉房里找到了他
We found him in an old abandoned boiler room...
他常抓小孩去那里
where he used to take his kids.
继续说
Go on.
我们把汽油
We took gasoline...
倒满在锅炉房四周
We poured it all around the place...
一直倒到门外
and made a trail of it out the door...
然后一把火把那里烧了
then lit the whole thing up and watched it burn.
他不能来害你了
But he can't get you now.
他死了  宝贝  妈妈杀死了他
He's dead, honey, because Mommy killed him.
我还拿走了他的刀
I even took his knives.
没事了
So it's OK now.
安心睡吧
You can sleep.
嗨  你好吗
Oh, hi, how you doing?
没事  你站在窗前  让我看到你
Fine. Stand by your window so I can see you.
听电话感觉好远
You sound a million miles away.
现在好多了
That's much better.
我今天看到你妈在保安店那里买东西
I see your mom went ape at the security store today.
你家现在就像座"古龙城堡"
You look like the Prisoner of Zenda or something.
你多久没睡过觉了
How long's it been since you slept?
今天是第七天了
It's coming up on the seventh day.
我查过健力士记录了
It's OK. I checked Guinness.
是11天我知道他是谁了
The record's 11.
听着  格伦
Listen, Glen, I know who he is.
他
Who?
那个凶手
The killer.
- 真的  - 没错
- You do? - Yes.
他杀了我后一定就会找你
And if he gets me, I'm pretty sure you're next.
为什么人人都想杀我
Why would anybody want to kill me?
你别管
Don't ask.
总之我要拉他出来
Just give me some help nailing the guy...
你要帮我
when I bring him out.
把他拉出来
Bring him out of what?
拉出梦境
My dream.
你要怎么做
How do you plan to do that?
就像拿那顶帽子一样
Just like I did the hat.
我抓住他时  你叫醒我
Have a hold of the sucker when you wake me up.
等一下
Wait a minute.
梦里的人怎么可能拉出来
You can't bring somebody out of a dream.
我也希望我做不到
If I can't, then you can all relax...
因为那就表示我只是疯了
because it's just a case of me being nuts.
放心好了
I can save you the trouble.
你一向疯疯癫癫
You're nutty as a fruitcake.
不过我还是喜欢你
I love you anyway.
好的
Good.
我把他从梦里拉出来后
Then you won't mind cold-cocking this guy...
你就痛扁他
when I bring him out.
什么
What?
我说了
You heard me.
我把那家伙拉出来
I grab the guy in my dream.
你看到我挣扎  就把我叫醒
You see me struggling, so you wake me up.
我们都出来后  你就痛扁那混蛋  把他逮住
We both come out, you whack the fucker, and we got him.
你疯了吗  我用什么打他
Are you crazy? Hit him with what?
拿出点男人气概来
You're the jock.
用棒球棍什么都好
You have a baseball bat or something.
你午夜时分来我家楼下
Just meet me at my porch at midnight.
还有就是
Oh, and meanwhile...
还有什么
Meanwhile?
不管怎么样  你都不能睡着
Whatever you do, don't fall asleep.
午夜
Midnight?
噢  老天
Oh, man.
午夜
Midnight.
用棒球棍打妖魔鬼怪
Baseball bats and bogeymen.
太棒了
Beautiful.
格伦
Honey?
你怎么一边看电视
How can you listen to television...
一边听歌呢
and hear your records at the same time?
我不用听电视声
Oh, I wasn't listening to the tube, Ma.
看就行了
Just watching.
今晚有美国小姐诞生
Miss Nude America is going to be on tonight.
你怎么听到她的话
How can you hear what she's going to say?
没人会听她说话
Who cares what she says?
小鬼头
Don't be such a smart guy.
快睡觉
I want you to go to bed.
快午夜了
It's almost midnight.
快休息吧
Goodness knows we've all had a lot to deal with...
这几天大家都忙坏了
these last few days.
我会的  妈
I will, Mom.
你们也睡了吗
You guys turning in?
快了
Pretty soon.
快上床睡觉
Now get to bed.
结束了  宝贝
It's over now, baby.
恶梦结束了  睡吧
The nightmare's over.
好吧
Please.
别盯着看了
You shouldn't stare.
你知道我在想什么吗
You know what I think?
我觉得那个女孩有点精神失常
I think that kid is some kind of lunatic.
别这么说人家  已经够可怜的了
You shouldn't talk that way about that poor child.
你看那些铁栏
You mean those bars?
马奇只是出于安全起见  现在就她们母女二人
Marge is just being cautious with her being all alone...
南希最近又精神紧张
and Nancy acting so nervous lately.
我不管你说什么
I don't care what you say.
我不想再让她再粘着我们的儿子
I don't want that kid hanging around with our son anymore.
格伦  快接电话
Glen, answer the phone.
等一下
Just a minute.
是她  她要找格伦
It's her. She wants to talk to Glen.
什么事
About what?
你有什么事  南希
What's this about, Nancy?
等一下
Just a minute.
她说这是私人的事
She says it's private.
私人的事  很重要
Very private and very important.
电话给我
Give me that.
格伦睡了  明天再打来吧
Glen's asleep. You'll have to talk to him tomorrow.
对待小孩子不能太温柔
You've just got to be firm with these kids.
走吧
Let's go.
最好是这样
As a matter of fact...
该死
Damn.
不要睡着
Don't fall asleep.
老天
Oh, brilliant.
如果格伦打电话来怎么办
What if Glen tries to call?
我是你的男友了  南希
I'm your boyfriend now, Nancy.
我的男友
My boyfriend.
妈
Mom!
锁上了  锁上了
Locked, locked, locked, locked.
我锁上了
I locked it all up.
我必须如此
I had to.
南希  除非你今晚睡觉
Nancy, you are going to get some sleep tonight...
乖乖听话
if it kills me.
钥匙给我  妈
Give me the key, Mother.
不行  我根本没带在身上
I can't. I don't even have it on me. See?
可恶
Damn it!
现在是午夜时分
It is now 12 midnight...
你收听的是KRGR电台空中节目
and this is station KRGR leaving the air.
救命  妈妈
Help, Mom!
快  法兰克  来帮个忙
Come on, Frank. I'll give you a hand.
不用拿担架了
You won't need a stretcher up there.
拿个拖把吧
You'll need a mop.
又是那种案件
Don't tell me it's another one.
汤母森警官  对不起  把你吵醒
Lieutenant Thompson, I'm sorry to wake you...
但我从没遇到过这种事
but I've never seen anything like this before in my life.
简直是闻所未闻
And I knew this is your neighborhood...
你是他们的邻居  所以我就想
so I thought I'd better call you right away.
最好找你来看看  验尸官在上面
The coroner's upstairs now, but I don't think that he's...
我的天
Oh, my God.
好  我这就叫他来
I'll get him right away.
队长  是你女儿的电话
Lieutenant, it's your daughter.
爸
Hi, Daddy.
我知道来龙去脉
I know what happened.
我还没上楼
I haven't been upstairs yet.
你知道他死了  对不对
But you know he's dead, right?
对  显然是死了
Yeah. Apparently he's dead.
爸爸  我有方法帮你破案
Listen, Daddy, I've got a proposition for you.
请你注意听
Listen very carefully, please.
我会去帮你把凶手拉出来
I'm going to go and get the guy who did it...
我把他拉出来时
and I want you to be there to arrest him...
你就当场抓住他  好吗
when I bring him out, OK?
告诉我是谁干的  我去抓他
Just tell me who did it. I'll go get him, baby.
是弗雷德  克鲁格干的  爸爸
Fred Krueger did it, Daddy...
只有我能抓住他
and only I can get him.
他一直在我梦里
It's my nightmare he comes to.
而且想追杀我
Just come here and break the door down...
20分钟后过来撞开我房门
in exactly 20 minutes.
- 可以吗  - 没问题
- Can you do that? - Yeah, sure.
要准时在12点半的时候
That'll be exactly half past midnight.
刚好够我睡着和把他拉出来
Time enough for me to fall asleep and find him.
宝贝  你先去睡吧
Honey, you just do that.
好好休息
Get yourself some sleep.
我经常叫你好好休息
That's what I've been telling you all along.
你真的会上来抓他
But you'll be here to catch him?
队长  他们在楼上等你
Lieutenant, they're waiting for you upstairs.
好的  我会去的  宝贝
Sure, I'll be there, sweetheart.
现在  你快去休息吧  知道吗
You just get yourself some rest... please?
好吧
Deal?
我爱你  宝贝
I love you, sweetheart.
你去看着我女儿的房间
Go outside and watch my daughter's house.
有事发生便找我
If you see anything funny, call me.
会有什么事
Anything funny, like what?
我也不知道
I don't know.
总之  我不想她来这里
One thing for sure, I don't want her coming over here.
她还不懂得处理这种情况
She's too far gone to be able to handle this.
是什么东西干的  队长
What the hell did that, Lieutenant?
我也不知道
I don't know.
验尸官怎么说
What has the coroner got to say?
他看到这番场景时就吐得不行了
He's in the john puking since he saw it.
我应该一早告诉你的
I guess I should have told you about him then.
你去睡吧  妈
Just get some sleep, Mom.
不会有事的
It's going to be OK.
我只想保护你
I was just trying to protect you.
我没想到这消息对你那么重要
I didn't see how much you needed to know.
你很勇敢
You face things.
是天性来的
That's your nature.
这是你的天赋
That's your gift...
但有时候你也必须逃避
but sometime you have to turn away, too.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你  宝贝
I love you, too, baby.
晚安
Night.
好吧  克鲁格
OK, Krueger.
我就来会一会你
We play on your court.
现在我躺下睡觉
And now I lay me down to sleep.
我向上帝祈祷
I pray the Lord my soul to keep...
如果我没办法醒来
and if I die before I wake...
愿主让我灵魂得到安息
I pray the Lord my soul to take.
倒计时开始
Countdown mode.
时限10分钟
Ten minutes and counting.
如果在梦里遇到怪物怎么办
What if they meet a monster in their dreams?
背向他
They turn their back on it.
用尽力气  他就会消失
Take away it's energy, and it disappears.
如果没有用呢
What happens if they don't do that?
那些人可能就无法醒来
Then I guess those people don't wake up to tell what happens.
跟你现身说法了
You dreamed about the same creep I did.
抓到你了
Gonna get you.
我来了
I'm here!
快给我出来  混蛋
Come out and show yourself, you bastard!
混蛋
Shit.
来啊  克鲁格
Come on, Krueger!
追我啊
Follow me!
可恶
Damn it!
你在哪
Where are you?
你在哪里  克鲁格
Where are you, Krueger?
我知道你在这里
I know you're here.
最后十秒
Final 10 seconds.
九  八  七  六
Nine, eight, seven, six...
南希
Bitch.
我抓到你了
I got you now!
我疯了吗
I'm crazy after all.
门开着的  克鲁格
Come on, Krueger!
追我啊
Take it down! Come and get me!
救命
Help!
我抓到他了  爸爸
I've got him! Hey, Daddy!
我困住他了
I've got him trapped!
救命  你在哪里
Help! Where are you?
没有事了
Everything's gonna be all right!
我们会处理好的
Everything's under control!
叫我爸来  混帐
Get my dad, you asshole!
快来
Come on!
他在这里
He's in here!
别让他杀我
Don't let him kill me, too!
过来啊
Come on, Freddy.
来抓我啊
Can't you catch me?
我要把你碎尸万段
I'm going to split you in two.
爸爸  救我
Daddy, help me, please!
看来我得去找队长来了
Maybe I better go tell the Lieutenant.
我要让你慢慢死
I'll kill you slow.
你在哪里
Where are you?
爸爸  我抓到他了
Daddy, I did it!
快来  爸
Please hurry!
你在哪里
Where are you?
帕克  快找人来
Parker, I need some help here!
好  你们几个快来
OK, you guys. Come on, let's go.
快过来
Let's go. Al, Tim, get over here.
快开门
Get you out.
门开着
Open this door!
保护好自己  我来抓他
Watch yourself. I got it.
克鲁格在这里
It's Krueger!
快让开
Get out of the way.
到这里来
This way, guys. Come down here.
天哪
Oh, my God.
南希  到底出什么事了
Nancy, what the hell is going on?
帕克  快上来
Parker, get up here!
来帮忙救火
We got a fire up here, too.
来了
We're on our way up.
到底是怎么回事  南希
What the hell is going on, Nancy?
他去找妈了
He's after Mother!
小心  他就在下面
Watch out! He's under there!
你现在相信我了吧
Now do you believe me?
他们在楼下救火
They've got the fires out downstairs.
这里不要紧吧
Everything OK up here?
我没事
I'm OK.
你先下楼
You go downstairs.
我马上下去
I'll be there in a minute.
真的没事吗
Lieutenant, is everything all right?
别问我
I don't know.
我知道你在这里  佛莱迪
I know you're there, Freddy.
你以为你能逃得掉吗
You think you was gonna get away from me?
我也了解你了  佛莱迪
I know you too well now, Freddy.
我要你死
Now you die.
太迟了  克鲁格
It's too late, Krueger.
我知道你的死穴
I know the secret now.
这只是个梦
This is just a dream.
你并不存在
You're not alive.
整件事是一场梦
This whole thing is just a dream.
我要我妈妈和朋友都回来
I want my mother and friends again.
什么
You what?
我要收回我给你的一切力量
I take back every bit of energy I gave you.
你什么都不是
You're nothing.
垃圾不如
You're shit.
真是惊喜
It's bright.
阳光普照  很快就会热的了  当心晒伤
It's going to burn off soon, or it wouldn't be so bright.
好一点了吗
Feeling better?
好得不得了
Oh, I feel like a million bucks.
他们说睡得好
They say you've bottomed out...
自然会记不起昨晚的梦
when you can't remember the night before.
看来我要戒酒了  宝贝
You know, baby, I'm going to stop drinking.
我好像不再爱喝酒了
I just don't feel like it anymore.
我昨晚吵醒你了吗
Did I keep you awake last night?
你精神有点不好
You look a little bit peaked.
我睡得非常好
I guess I just slept heavy.
回头见
I'll see you.
See you.
大家好
Hi, everybody.
怎么起雾了
You believe this fog?
什么事都有可能发生
I believe anything is possible.
你今天好靓
Looking good, girl.
怎么了
What happened?
怎么回事
What's going on?
我什么都没做
Hey, I'm not doing this.
格伦  快让我们出去
Let us out!
不是我关的
I'm not doing this.
车窗怎么关上了
What's going on with the window?
不  妈妈
No! Mother!
怎么回事
What's going on?
一  二  佛莱迪要来抓你了
One, two... Freddy's coming for you.
三  四
Three, four...
最好把门锁紧
Better lock your door.
五  六
Five, six...
快去拿十字架
Grab your crucifix.
七  八
Seven, eight...
彻夜不眠
Gonna stay up late.
九  十
Nine, ten...
永远不要睡
Never sleep again.